Guide to the Western Silent Films Lobby Card Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Western silent films lobby card collection
1912-1930
WA MSS S-2553
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
3.5
(3 boxes)
Collection consists of 105 items (86 lobby cards and 19 printed fliers) promoting sixty-eight films, mostly silent westerns, from the 1910's and 1920's. Lobby cards and fliers include both photographic and artistic renderings of scenes and characters from the publicized film.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Walter Reuben on the Frederick W. and Carrie S. Beinecke Fund for Western Americana, 2006.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The Western Silent Films Lobby Cards Collection consists of 106 printed items used to promote silent and western films, ca. 1910-ca. 1930. 87 lobby cards and 19 printed fliers have been arranged alphabetically under each film title. Titles of lobby cards were transcribed from captions or supplied if no caption was present. The lobby cards and publicity fliers include both photographic and artistic renderings of scenes and characters from the film being publicized.
Sixty-eight silent films are represented in the collection as well as an early sound motion picture released in 1928, The Trail of '98.
Complete lobby card sets (consisting of eight 11 x 14 lobby cards) are present for The Covered Wagon, a 1923 silent western starring J. Warren Kerrigan and Lois Wilson; The Thundering Herd, a 1925 film based on Zane Grey's novel featuring Jack Holt, Lois Wilson, and Noah Beery; and The Tough Guy, a 1926 western that billed Fred Thomson, Lola Todd, and Silver King the Horse as leads. Fred Thomson and Silver King the Horse are also promoted as leads in The Sunset Legion, The Two-Gun Man, and The Wild Bull's Lair. Other non-human actors represented in the collection include Rex the Wonder Horse (in a flier for 1927's No Man's Law ) and Ranger the Dog (in a flier for 1929's The One Man Dog ).
Movie actors featured in more than one film title in the collection include Art Acord ( The Circus Cylcone (1925), Custer's Last Fight (1912), The Squaw Man (1914), Three in Exile (1925), The Western Rover (1927)); Noah Beery ( In Mizzoura (1919), Wanderer of the Wasteland (1924)); Harry Carrey ( The Flaming Forties (1924), The Fox (1921), Good Men and True (1922)); Franklyn Farnum ( Smiling Jim (1922), Wolves of the Border (1923)); William S. Hart ( The Disciple (1915), The Testing Block (1920), White Oak (1921)); Jack Holt ( The Enchanted Hill (1926), Wanderer of the Wasteland (1924), The Water Hole (1928)); Jack Hoxie ( Lightning Bryce (1919), Wolf Tracks (1923)); Tom Mix ( The Great K & A Train Robbery (1926), The Rainbow Trail (1925)); Buddy Roosevelt ( The Bandit Buster (1926), The Ramblin' Galoot (1926)); and Ted Wells ( The Smiling Terror (1929), Thunder Riders (1928)).
Other movie actors that appear in the collection include Roscoe "Fatty" Arbuckle in The Round-Up and Douglas Fairbanks in The Mollycoddle (1920). Also present are lobby cards or fliers for films starring Don Coleman and Ben Corbett ( The Bronc Stomper (1928)), William Conklin ( The Drifters (1919)), William Duncan ( Playing It Wild (1923)), Dustin Farnum ( The Squaw Man (1914)), William Farnum ( The Gunfighter (1916)), Francis Ford ( Custer's Last Stand (1912)), Hoot Gibson ( King of the Rodeo (1929)), Neil Hamilton ( Desert Gold (1926)), Kenneth Harlan ( The Virginian (1923)), Buck Jones ( The Timber Wolf (1925)), George Larkin ( Beauty and the Bandit (1921)), Jack Luden ( Shootin' Irons (1927)), John Mason ( The Fatal Card (1915)), Frank Mayo ( The Red Lane (1920)), Ken Maynard ( The Glorious Trail (1928)), J. P. McGowan ( Discontented Wives (1921)), Malcolm McGregor ( Broken Chains (1922)), Burr McIntosh ( My Partner (1916)), Pete Morrison ( The Ghost City (1923)), Conrad Nagel ( The Michigan Kid (1928)), Charles Ray ( Deuce of Spades (1922)), Lewis Stone ( The Golden Snare (1921)), and Ernest Torrence ( Broken Chains (1922)).
Lobby cards and fliers for films starring the following actresses are present: Mary Astor ( Rose of the Golden West (1927)), Ann Cornwall ( The Rainbow Trail (1925)), Grace Cunard ( Custer's Last Fight (1912)), Bebe Daniels ( Rio Rita (1929)), Josephine Hill ( Beauty and the Bandit (1921)), Edith Johnson ( Playing It Wild (1923)), Jacqueline Logan ( Salomy Jane (1923)), Louise Lorraine ( Three in Exile (1925)), Bessie Love ( Sundown (1924)), Shirley Mason ( Desert Gold (1926)), Doris May ( The Gunfighter (1923)), Colleen Moore ( Broken Chains (1922)), Gloria Swanson ( Station Content (1918)), Alice Terry ( Sackcloth and Scarlet (1925)), and Lois Wilson ( The Drifters (1919)).
Bandit buster (Motion picture); Beauty and the bandit (Motion picture); Broken chains (Motion picture); Bronc stomper (Motion picture); Circus cyclone (Motion picture); Covered wagon (Motion picture); Custer's last fight (Motion picture); Desert gold (Motion picture); Deuce of spades (Motion picture); Discipulo (Motion picture); Discontented wives (Motion picture); Drifters (Motion picture); Enchanted hill (Motion picture); Fatal card (Motion picture); Flaming forties (Motion picture); Fox (Motion picture); Ghost city (Motion picture); Glorious trail (Motion picture); Golden snare (Motion picture); Good men and true (Motion picture); Great K & A train robbery (Motion picture); Gunfighter (Motion picture); Horseman of the plains (Motion picture); In Mizzoura (Motion picture); King of the rodeo (Motion picture); Kit Carson (Motion picture); Lightning Bryce (Motion picture); Man from Hell's River (Motion picture); Michigan kid (Motion picture); Mollycoddle (Motion picture); My partner (Motion picture); No man's law (Motion picture); One man dog (Motion picture); Playing it wild (Motion picture); Pony Express (Motion picture); Rainbow trail (Motion picture); Ramblin' galoot (Motion picture); Red lane (Motion picture); Rio Rita (Motion picture); Rose of the golden west (Motion picture); Round-up (Motion picture); Sackcloth and scarlet (Motion picture); Salomy Jane (Motion picture); Shootin' irons (Motion picture); Smiling Jim (Motion picture); Smiling terror (Motion picture); Squaw man (Motion picture); Station content (Motion picture); Sundown (Motion picture); Sunset legion (Motion picture); Testing block (Motion picture); Three in exile (Motion picture); Thunder riders (Motion picture); Thundering herd (Motion picture); Timber wolf (Motion picture); Tough guy (Motion picture); Trail of '98 (Motion picture); Two-gun man (Motion picture); Virginian (Motion picture); Wanderer of the wasteland (Motion picture); Water hole (Motion picture); Western rover (Motion picture); When men hate (Motion picture); White oak (Motion picture); Wild bull's lair (Motion picture); Winners of the wilderness (Motion picture); Wolf tracks (Motion picture); Wolves of the border (Motion picture); Film posters, American; Motion picture actors and actresses -- Posters; Motion picture programs; Silent films -- Posters; Western films -- Posters; Fliers; Lobby cards
- Lobby Cards and Fliers, 1912-1930; Series I; 1.84; (2 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Lobby Cards and Fliers is organized by film title. Posters and fliers for each film title are arranged alphabetically.
  - The Bandit Buster (1926)
    - "Buddy is taken by surprise," lobby card, 11 x 14, [1926?] (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - "Buddy points at the hide-out of the bandits," lobby card, 11 x 14, [1926?] (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "A tight corner for the bandit buster," lobby card, 11 x 14, [1926?] (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Beauty and the Bandit (1921)
    - "A Mustang picture, Beauty and the Bandit..." lobby card, 11 x 14, [1921?] (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Broken Chains (1922)
    - "Her husband, the cruelest man in Arizona, returns unexpectedly," lobby card, 11 x 14, [1922?] (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - "When I get through with him there won't be anything to love," lobby card, 11 x 14, [1922?] (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - The Bronc Stomper (1928)
    - "Rescued from the flooded river," lobby card, 11 x 14, [1928?] (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - "Thurston disarms the gambler," lobby card, 11 x 14, [1928?] (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - "Thurston's unexpected attack wins him his liberty," lobby card, 11 x 14, [1928?] (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - The Circus Cyclone (1925)
    - "Art Acord in 'The Circus Cyclone'..." lobby card, 11 x 14, [1925?] (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - The Covered Wagon (1923)
    - [Drawing of covered wagon on prairie being drawn by horses, with cow], title lobby card, 11 x 14, [1923?] (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - [Drawing of mounted cowboy rescuing woman from prairie fire], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1923?] (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - [Drawing of hero and heroine in embrace], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1923?] (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - [Drawing of Indians on horseback attacking circled wagons], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1923?] (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - [Drawing of two men crouching over a dead man against prarie landscape], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1923?] (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - [Drawing of upset wagons and people fording river], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1923?] (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - [Drawing of wagon train with yelling Indian in foreground], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1923?] (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - [Drawing of western town exterior with man behind table of bottles aiming shotgun at man with cup on his head], [1923?] (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Promotional flier, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Stamped on last leaf: "Girard Opera House, Mar. 16 & 17, 15 and 35"
    - Promotional newspaper flier, 16 x 22, n.d.
  - Custer's Last Fight (1912)
    - Promotional flier, [1912?] (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Desert Gold (1926)
    - Promotional flier, [1926?] (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Deuce of Spades (1922)
    - "Say Bub, whatcha goin' to do with that artillery?" lobby card, 11 x 14, [1922?] (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - The Disciple (1915)
    - [Sienna photograph of William S. Hart drawing pistol in front of crowd on stairs], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1915?] (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - [Sienna photograph of William S. Hart in doorway of log cabin, with woman sobbing on table and two men], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1915?] (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Discontented Wives (1921)
    - "We'll keep it a secret from Ruth until it's assayed," lobby card, 11 x 14, [1921?] (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - The Drifters (1919)
    - "And so he brought her in!" lobby card, 11 x 14, [1919?] (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - "Partners-- but enemies," lobby card, 11 x 14, [1919?] (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - The Enchanted Hill (1926)
    - [Crowd of armed men standing outside adobe ranch, addressing Chinese character in doorway], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1926?] (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - The Fatal Card (1915)
    - Publicity flier, [1915?] (Box 1, Folder 29)
      With manuscript annotations on verso
  - The Flaming Forties (1924)
    - [Harry Carrey fighting with another man], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1924?] (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - The Fox (1921)
    - [Harry Carrey on horseback consults with a Mountie in foreground; other Mounties in background], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1921?] (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - [Harry Carrey on horseback in front of line of cowboys in front of rocky mountainside], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1921?] (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - The Ghost City (1923)
    - [Cowboy Pete Morrison in portrait with background art by Jack Savage], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1923?] (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - The Glorious Trail (1928)
    - [Cowboy Ken Maynard with drawn pistols in front of heroine], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1928?] (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - The Golden Snare (1921)
    - "The mad Loup Garou suddenly loomed before him," lobby card, 11 x 14, [1921?] (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Good Men and True (1922)
    - "A crash - a shriek - and he plunged over the sandy precipice," lobby card, 11 x 14, [1922?] (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - The Great K & A Train Robbery (1926)
    - [Two men on horse diving from veranda], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1926?] (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - The Gunfighter (1923)
    - [William Farnum, bandaged, with heroine and older man], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1923?] (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - [William Farnum being held by other men in street], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1923?] (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - [William Farnum posed with horse and heroine], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1923?] (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Horseman of the Plains (1928)
    - Title lobby card, 11 x 14, [1928?] (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - In Mizzoura (1919)
    - "Tell the boys to follow. He has taken the old logging road," lobby card, 8 x 10, [1919?] (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - King of the Rodeo (1929)
    - "The biggest western ever screened!", title lobby card, 11 x 14, [1929?] (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - "Whoopee-e!", title lobby card, 11 x 14 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Kit Carson (1928)
    - Publicity flier, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Lightning Bryce (1919)
    - "Episode Ten 'Poison Waters'," lobby card, 11 x 14, [1919?] (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Man From Hell's River (1922)
    - Title lobby card, 11 x 14, [1922?] (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Michigan Kid (1928)
    - "Jimmy, I'm afraid -- we'll never reach the river alive!" lobby card, 11 x 14, [1928?] (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Publicity flier, [1929] (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - The Mollycoddle (1920)
    - Lobby card, 11 x 14, [1920?] (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - My Partner (1916)
    - Publicity flier, [1916?] (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - No Man's Law (1927)
    - Publicity flier, [1927?] (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - The One Man Dog (1929)
    - Publicity flier, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Playing It Wild (1923)
    - [Two scenes depicting Edith Johnson with suitor; lower image of cowboys gambling], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1923?] (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - [William Duncan on horse in lower right; scene of Duncan visiting Edith Johnson and father in her home, upper left], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1923?] (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - The Pony Express (1925)
    - [Pony Express rider aiming at Indian riding away from burning fort], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1925?] (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - [Pony Express rider attacked by three Indians], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1925?] (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - The Rainbow Trail (1925)
    - [Tom Mix comforting Anne Cornwall in cabin], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1925?] (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - The Ramblin' Galoot (1926)
    - "Buddy Roosevelt in 'The Ramblin' Galoot'," lobby card, 11 x 14, [1926?] (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - The Red Lane (1920)
    - "Frank Mayo in 'The Red Lane'," lobby card, 11 x 14, [1920?] (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Rio Rita (1929)
    - Publicity flier, [1930] (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Rose of the Golden West (1927)
    - Publicity flier, [1927?] (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - The Round-Up (1920)
    - "Slim breaks the news to Echo of Dick's death," lobby card, 11 x 14, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Sackcloth and Scarlet (1925)
    - "Robert Kane presents Henry King's Sackcloth and Scarlet with Alice Terry ..." lobby card, 11 x 14, [1925?] (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Salomy Jane (1923)
    - "Jesse L. Lasky presents Salomy Jane ..." lobby card, 11 x 14, [1923?] (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - "Jesse L. Lasky presents Salomy Jane ..." lobby card, 11 x 14, [1923?] (Box 1, Folder 65a)
  - Shootin' Irons (1927)
    - "Jack Luden in Shootin' Irons..." lobby card, 11 x 14, [1927?] (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Smiling Jim (1922)
    - [Cowboy with pistol in doorway of bar, holding up crowd of men], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1922?] (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - The Smiling Terror (1929)
    - "Ted Wells in 'The Smiling Terror'..." lobby card, 11 x 14, [1929?] (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Station Content (1918)
    - "Triangle plays," lobby card, 11 x 14, [1918?] (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - The Squaw Man (1914)
    - Publicity flier, [1914?] (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Sundown (1924)
    - Publicity flier, [1924?] (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - The Sunset Legion (1928)
    - Publicity flier, [1928] (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - The Testing Block (1920)
    - "I'll take this, Sheriff,-- might look nice tacked up in my office," lobby card, 11 x 14, [1920?] (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Three in Exile (1925)
    - "'Three in Exile' with Louise Lorraine ..." lobby card, 11 x 14, [1925?] (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Thunder Riders (1928)
    - "Thunder Riders," lobby card, 11 x 14, [1928?] (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - The Thundering Herd (1925)
    - "Adolph Zukor and Jesse L. Lasky present Zane Grey's The Thundering Herd..." lobby card, 11 x 14, [1925?] (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - [Cowboy on horseback converses with leader of wagon train], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1925?] (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - [Drawing of Jack Holt and others shooting at attacking Indians], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1925?] (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - [Drawing of Lois Wilson and Noah Beery standing over fallen figure of Jack Holt], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1925?] (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - [Drawing of Lois Wilson confronting Noah Beery], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1925?] (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - [Noah Beery, held back by Raymond Hutton, lunges towards Jack Holt and Lois Wilson], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1925?] (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - [Lois Wilson and cowboy, with bullwhip in foreground], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1925?] (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - [Raymond Hutton, Noah Beery and Jack Holt holding knives, sitting on boxes on open plain], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1925?] (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - The Timber Wolf (1925)
    - "William Fox presents Buck Jones in The Timber Wolf x 14, [1925?] (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - The Tough Guy (1926)
    - "Film Book Offices presents Fred Thomson with his famous horse Silver King..." lobby card, 11 x 14, [1926?] (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - [Fred Thomson assisting lady riding side saddle on white horse], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1926?] (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - [Fred Thomson bringing flowers to schoolteacher], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1926?] (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - [Fred Thomson comforting woman resting on table], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1926?] (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - [Fred Thomson embraces woman as crowd of older women look on], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1926?] (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - [Fred Thomson hanging over door and embracing woman], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1926?] (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - [Fred Thomson holding book and looking upwards with woman at his side], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1926?] (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - [Fred Thomson petting white horse, with arm around a clergy man], lobby card, 11 x 14, [1926?] (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - The Trail of '98 (1928)
    - Publicity flier, [1928?] (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - The Two-Gun Man (1926)
    - "Fred Thomson and his wonderful horse -- Silver King in 'The Two-Gun Man'," lobby card, 11 x 14, [1926?] (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - The Virginian (1923)
    - Publicity flier, [1923?] (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - Wanderer of the Wasteland (1924)
    - "Zane Grey's Wanderer of the Wasteland..." lobby card, 11 x 14, [1924?] (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - The Water Hole (1928)
    - "Zane Grey's The Water Hole with Jack Holt and Nancy Carroll..." lobby card, 11 x 14, [1928?] (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - The Western Rover (1927)
    - "Art Acord in 'The Western Rover'..." lobby card, 11 x 14, [1927?] (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - When Men Hate (1913)
    - Publicity flier, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - White Oak (1921)
    - "William S. Hart in 'White Oak'..." lobby card, 11 x 14, [1921?] (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - The Wild Bull's Lair (1925)
    - "F.B.O. presents Fred Thomson and his famous horse Silver King in 'The Wild Bull's Lair'..." lobby card, 11 x 14, [1925?] (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - Winners of the Wilderness (1927)
    - Publicity flier, [1927?] (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - Wolf Tracks (1923)
    - "Anthony J. Xydias presents Jack Hoxie in 'Wolf Tracks'..." lobby card, 11 x 14 (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - Wolves of the Border (1923)
    - "Franklyn Farnum in 'Wolves of the Border'..." lobby card, 11 x 14, [1923?] (Box 2, Folder 104)
- Oversize, 1.67; (1 box)
  - Promotional newspaper flier ( Covered Wagon ), n.d. (Box 3, Folder 105)